Guide to the Bicentennial Committee, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Bicentennial Committee, Yale University, records
1898-1901
RU 155
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.75
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, minutes, and reports documenting the activities of Yale's Bicentennial Committee. Included are materials of the Executive Committee, the Art and Decoration Committee, the Entertainment Committee, the Committee on Honorary Degrees, and the Committee on Guests.
Yale University. Bicentennial Committee
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 6 (YRG 6), Records of Yale Committees.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, minutes, and reports documenting the activities of Yale's Bicentennial Committee. Included are materials of the Executive Committee, the Art and Decoration Committee, the Entertainment Committee, the Committee on Honorary Degrees, and the Committee on Guests.
Anniversaries; Yale University -- Anniversaries, etc.; Yale University -- Centennial celebrations, etc.; Yale University -- History; Yale University. Bicentennial Committee
- Records, 1898-1901; Accession 1932-A-004
  - Executive Committee: Correspondence, 1898-1901
    - An - Ba (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ba - Be (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Be - Bo (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bo - Br (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Br - Bu (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bu - Ca (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ca - Ch (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ch - Co (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Co - Da (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - De (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - De - Du (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Du - Ed (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Eg - Fa (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Fa - Fi (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Fi (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Fi - Fo (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Fo - Gi (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Go - Ha (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Ha - Hi (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Hi - Is (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Iv - Ja (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Ja - Ke (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Ki - La (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - La -Ma (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Ma (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
    - Mc - Mo (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Mo -Ne (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Ne - Ni (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - No (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - No - Pe (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Pe - Re (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Re - Ro (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Ro-Sc (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Sc (Box 3, Folder 35-36)
    - Sc-Sh (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Sh - St (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - St - Sw (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Ta - Ti (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Ti - We (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - We - Wh (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Wh - Yo (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Index (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Art & Decoration Committee: Correspondence
    - Mar. - Apr., 1898 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Apr.- Dec., 1898 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Jan. - May, 1899 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Jul. - Oct., 1899 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Oct. - Dec, 1899 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Dec. - Jul., 1899-1900 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Jul. - Nov., 1900 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Nov. - Dec., 1900 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Dec. - Feb., 1900-1901 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Feb. - Mar., 1901 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Mar. - Apr., 1901 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Apr. - Sep., 1901 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Committee on Entertainment, 1901
    - Journal, Expenses, Cash Account (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Sub-Committee on Entertainment: Information on Accommodations, Tickets, Forms, Registration Cards (Box 5, Folder 58)
      General
      See also:Box 7
  - Committee on Guests, 1901
    - Minutes (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - A - C (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - D - G (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - H - L (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - M - O (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - P - S (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - T - Y (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Committee on Honorary Degrees, 1901
    - General (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Candidates
      - A - G (Box 6, Folder 68)
      - H - M (Box 6, Folder 69)
      - N - W (Box 6, Folder 70)
    - and Committee on Printing, Minutes, 1900-1901 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Subcommittee on Celebration of the Bicentennial Minutes, 1898-1901 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Printed Material, Invitations, and Memorabilia
    - Other Schools Receiving Invitations to Celebration, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Newspaper Clippings, September 1901 (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - Other Clippings, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - Memorabilia - Button, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Registration cards (Box 7)
    General note
    See also: box 5, folder 57
- "Greek Festival Hymn" for the bicentennial of the founding of Yale College, 1901; Accession 1994-A-127
  - "Greek Festival Hymn" for the bicentennial of the founding of Yale College, 1901 (Box 1)
- Notebooks containing the official invitations list to the Yale Bicentennial, 1901; Accession 1995-A-061
  - Notebooks containing the official invitations list to the Yale Bicentennial, 1901 (Box 1)